Inventory of the United States. Federal Security Agency Phonorecords, 1939
Hoover Institution Archives
United States. Federal Security Agency Phonorecords,
1939
72029
United States. Federal Security Agency
Number of Items: 24 phonorecords 2.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Relates to the immigration of various nationalities and ethnic groups to the U.S.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The Federal Security Agency was created by the President's Reorganization Plan No. I of 1939, effective July 1, 1939, as an organization for the promotion of social and economic security, educational opportunity, and health. Upon its creation the FSA had oversight responsibility for the following constituent units transferred from other agencies: Office of Education, Public Health Service, National Youth Administration, Civilian Conservation Corps, Social Security Board, and U.S. Employment Service. The Radio Division and U.S. Film Service were transferred from the Department of the Treasury and incorporated into the Office of Education by Reorganization Plan No. II of 1939, effective July 1, 1939.
The agency's functions were not changed during World War II, but within their general scope the agency's activities were in certain respects altered or expanded to deal with special situations that were directly attributable to the war.
The FSA was abolished by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1953, effective April 11, 1953, with functions transferred to the newly established Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.
Access Points
United States--Politics and government.; United States--Emigration and immigration.; Phonorecords.
Container List
- "Americans All, Immigrants All"
  - Near Eastern People, 1939 March 12 (Item 1.)
  - Jews in the United States, 1939 February 5 (Item 2.)
  - Contributors in Industry, undated (Item 3.)
  - Italians in America, 1939 March 5 (Item 4.)
  - Irish, undated (Item 5.)
  - Winning Freedom, undated (Item 6.)
  - Social Progress, undated (Item 7.)
  - Our English Heritage, undated (Item 8.)
  - An Industrial City, undated (Item 9.)
  - French in America, undated (Item 10.)
  - German, undated (Item 11.)
  - Orientals in America, undated (Item 12.)
  - A New England Town, undated (Item 13.)
  - Hispanic Heritage, undated (Item 14.)
  - Slavs in America, 1939 February 12 (Item 15.)
  - Slavs in America, 1939 February 19 (Item 16.)
  - Contributors in Science, undated (Item 17.)
  - Scotch Irish, undated (Item 18.)
  - Arts and Crafts, undated (Item 19.)
  - Scandinavian, undated (Item 20.)
  - Other groups, undated (Item 21.)
  - Closing Frontier, undated (Item 22.)
  - Grand Finale, undated (Item 23.)
- Treasury Department. War Savings Staff. Radio recordings, undated (Item 24.)
  - "Treasury Star Parade" presenting "Mr. Jones and Mr. Washington"
  - "Treasury Star Parade, the Songs of the United Nations" starring Vincent Price and Igor Gorin